LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

KRIS RENALDI

South Plainfield, NJ | (732) 593-7798 | krenaldi@comcast.net

SUMMARY

Dedicated IT professional with extensive customer service, technical training and management, and project managing experience with expertise in web development and network administration and desire to learn new things. Discipline in the following:

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API, JSON, SQL, SASS

Tools: Git/GitHub, Gulp, NPM, Node, MySQL, Heroku, Firebase

Libraries/Frameworks: Bootstrap, Express, REACT, ¡Query, MongoDB, Backbone, Knockout

Software: Visual Studio, MS Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook & Visio, Adobe Photoshop & Acrobat

Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, UNIX, Linux, Cisco

CERTIFICATIONS

| Front-End Web Developer, Udacity | 2015 |
|--|------|
| Six-Sigma Green Belt | 2009 |
| Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA) | 2004 |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AT&T, Piscataway, NJ

December 1998 – May 2019

VPN Technical Manager, October 2015 – May 2019

Issued and monitored activation of VPN service for high profile customers such as Bank of Montreal. Led online training for domestic new hires who were managing the installation and activation of VPN with BVOIP service.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance by having my orders activated and billed before target of 90 days and was consistently a top 5 performer on the team.
- Reduced backlog of 600+ open orders by 80% with overseas team.

MIS/BVOIP Technical Manager, April 2010 - October 2015

Managed MIS and BVOIP ordering team located overseas in the Philippines where my team worked on large projects for Panera Bread and J.C. Penney. Provided in-person training and onboarding support at overseas office. Developed and updated training documentation and assisted with support for MIS and BVOIP ordering.

 Slashed end-to-end cycle time for service ordering by several days and reduced number of rejects and defects to almost zero with the overseas team.

New Hire Trainer / Process Engineer, September 2008 - April 2010

Trained new hire agents for MIS & BVOIP service ordering. Developed new hire training documentation and assisted with the onboarding process for MIS and BVOIP ordering. Spearheaded testing of all systems and applications to ensure proper functionality and documentation of BVOIP ordering process.

• Earned Six Sigma Green Belt and worked with Quality Management team on a Service Delivery Six Sigma Project to streamline the process for a BVOIP product which saved the company an estimated \$823K annually.

MIS Provisioning Technical Engineer / Trainer, May 2000 - September 2008

Provisioned MIS and MPLS-PNT service for customers and led new hire training for MIS Provisioning Technical Engineers. Project Manager and Leader for several high-profile clients such as La-Z-Boy, Pepsi, Office Depot, and Motel 6.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance with an average of 98% (exceeding the target of 90-95%) and Cycle Time with an average of 28 days (shorter than the target of 30 days). As a result of my performance, my team exceeded the On-Time Performance target with a 96% average and Cycle Time of 29 days.
- Earned 7 Commitment to Excellence awards awarded by customers and sales account teams for providing outstanding customer service.

Content Author/Manager, December 1998 - May 2000

Converted and updated technical documentation to HTML for publication on AT&T's internal Content Management System which gave the provisioning and technical support teams a single resource to pull information on how to perform their job functions.

- Re-designed the layout and architecture of the site for easier search capabilities for end users.
- Set up and maintained UNIX Web Server for developing and testing web applications that employees used to make their job function easier.

Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/

GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

Kris Renaldi krenaldi@comcast.net Page 2

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

BlastNet ISP, Whitehouse Station, NJ

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi

Position: Webmaster - Designed websites for local small businesses and maintained UNIX web servers for Web-hosting Services for Internet Service Provider. Worked on front-end features for e-commerce websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and some PERL scripting.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media & Political Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ, Sept 1993 – May 1997 Full Stack Web Development, Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ, May 2019 - Oct 2019